Academic success. Module five. So the objectives are use evidence-based study techniques, specifically retrieval practice and space practice. Very important.
Explain why common techniques like rereading and highlighting are less effective.
Build a weekly study schedule that fits how college courses actually distribute the work and communicate proactively professors.
You know, a lot of these objectives actually have to have everything to do with the previous modules. Module one, you know, the form rules of college, go to office hours, read the syllabus.
I've been, you know, I've been in STEM majors. I switched my majors four times, actually, but three of those were STEM.
And biology, you know, I didn't really know how to study that because it's a lot of memorization. I was doing rereading and highlighting when, you know, I had no idea what retrieval practice or space practice was.
I didn't really know how to study because I truly am a humanities major. I love writing. I can write essays on the spot, but you might not be, and you may be a STEM major who memorizes things really easily and knows how to implement those things.
So just make sure you're using the correct study techniques, highlighting things, rereading things. It may seem like you're doing something, but it's not. You know, I've used, use your resources to free resources.
I'm not sure if Quizlet's free anymore, but flashcard resources. Very important.
Build a weekly study schedule, especially if you're in a major that requires a lot of memorization.
If you're setting aside at least some time to study per week, making sure that everything on the syllabus is well aligned that, you know, when the next tests or the next midterms are.
This is how you achieve academic success. I've been in situations where I was really just downright close to failing a class because I didn't really know how to study it.
So make sure you're also just included with the studying, talk to your professors, go to office hours, make sure that you guys are both on the same page. They are not your enemy. They're here to help you. They want to pass you.
So make sure you use those resources as well.